A Guide to the James P. Roberts Photograph Collection, 2003-
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
James P. Roberts Photograph Collection 2003-
Thomas Balch Library
VC 0019
The 204 4"x6" color photographs in this collection primarily document Loudoun County Public School buildings from the fall of 2007 through the fall of 2009.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
James P. Roberts, Leesburg, VA
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2007.0116, 2007.0179, 2007.0178, 2008.0078, 2008.0081, 2003.0043, 2008.0153, 2009.0060, 2009.0167, 2009.0136, 2009.0167
Biographical Information
Avocational photographer James P. Roberts is a life-time Loudoun County, Virginia resident. Born and raised in segregated Leesburg, he graduated from Douglass High School. He served in the U.S. Navy for five years before returning to Loudoun County to raise his family.
Roberts organized the first African American Boy Scout troop in Middleburg, which later became the first integrated troop. He was also the first African American awarded Middleburg's Fireman of the Year award and co-founded the Windy Hill Foundation. Roberts served on the Middleburg Town Council in 1980 and on the Thomas Balch Library Advisory Commission since 2001.
In addition to his volunteer activities, Roberts is actively involved in preserving Loudoun County history. He regularly leads a walking tour exploring local people, places and points of interest both in and around Leesburg. He shares his first-hand knowledge of how Leesburg has grown and evolved through the years architecturally, economically, and racially. In recognition of his contributions, Roberts was a Loudoun History Award recipient in 2008.
Scope and Content
The 204 4"x6" color photographs in this collection primarily document Loudoun County Public School buildings from the fall of 2007 through the fall of 2009.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
History Awards Nomination, 2008, Town of Leesburg Records, Thomas Balch Library Advisory Commission (RG08), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
James P. Roberts, interview with Beth Schuster, 18 September 2009.
James P. Roberts Photograph Collection (VC 0019), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Thomas Balch Library, Town of Leesburg, www.leesburgva.gov/ThomasBalchLibrary, accessed 17 September 2009
Other Finding Aid
PastPerfect catalogue records
Technical Requirements
None
Related Material
Black History Committee Oral History Project, M012; Thomas Balch Library Vertical Files -- Schools
Contents List
- [Hamilton Elementary], 2007
- [Harmony Intermediate], 2007
- [Harmony Intermediate], 2007
- [Harmony Intermediate], 2007
- [Loudoun Valley High], 2007
- [Loudoun Valley High], 2007
- [Mountain View Elementary], 2007
- [Mountain View Elementary], 2007
- [Banneker Elementary], 2007
- [Banneker Elementary], 2007
- [Middleburg Elementary], 2007
- [Middleburg Elementary], 2007
- [Middleburg Elementary], 2007
- [Mercer Middle], 2007
- [Mercer Middle], 2007
- [Pinebrook Elementary], 2007
- [Pinebrook Elementary], 2007
- [Pinebrook Elementary], 2007
- [Little River Elementary], 2007
- [Little River Elementary], 2007
- [Hutchison Farm Elementary], 2007
- [Hutchison Farm Elementary], 2007
- [Hutchison Farm Elementary], 2007
- [Freedom High], 2007
- [Freedom High], 2007
- [Freedom High], 2007
- [Freedom High], 2007
- [Freedom High], 2007
- [Legacy Elementary], 2007
- [Legacy Elementary], 2007
- [Briar Woods High], 2007
- [Briar Woods High], 2007
- [Briar Woods High], 2007
- [Newton-Lee Elementary], 2007
- [Newton-Lee Elementary], 2007
- [Harper Park Middle], 2007
- [Harper Park Middle], 2007
- [John W. Tolbert Elementary], 2007
- [John W. Tolbert Elementary], 2007
- Cochran Mill, 2007
- Cochran Mill, 2007
- Cochran Mill, 2007
- Cochran Mill, 2007
- [Broad Run High], 2007
- [Broad Run High], 2007
- [Broad Run High], 2007
- [Sanders Corner Elementary], 2007
- [Sanders Corner Elementary], 2007
- [Sterling Elementary], 2007
- [Sterling Elementary], 2007
- [Park View High], 2007
- [Park View High], 2007
- [Sully Elementary], 2007
- [Sully Elementary], 2007
- [Sterling Middle], 2007
- [Sterling Middle], 2007
- [Sterling Middle], 2007
- [Forest Grove Elementary], 2007
- [Forest Grove Elementary], 2007
- [Rolling Ridge Elementary], 2007
- [Rolling Ridge Elementary], 2007
- [Frances Hazel Reid Elementary], 2007
- [Frances Hazel Reid Elementary], 2007
- [Frances Hazel Reid Elementary], 2007
- [Smart's Mill Middle], 2007
- [Smart's Mill Middle], 2007
- [Smart's Mill Middle], 2007
- [Seldens Landing Elementary], 2007
- [Seldens Landing Elementary], 2007
- [Belmont Ridge Middle], 2007
- [Belmont Ridge Middle], 2007
- [Belmont Station Elementary], 2007
- [Belmont Station Elementary], 2007
- [Stone Bridge High], 2007
- [Stone Bridge High], 2007
- [Cedar Lane Elementary], 2007
- [Cedar Lane Elementary], 2007
- [Hillside Elementary], 2007
- [Hillside Elementary], 2007
- [Mill Run Elementary], 2007
- [Mill Run Elementary], 2007
- [Eagle Ridge Middle], 2007
- 2007[Eagle Ridge Middle]
- [Eagle Ridge Middle], 2007
- [Sycolin Creek Elementary], 2008
- [Sycolin Creek Elementary], 2008
- [Meadowland Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Meadowland Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Meadowland Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Algonkian Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Algonkian Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Dominion Trail Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Farmwell Station Middle], 2008-06-06
- [Sugarland Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Dominion High], 2008-06-06
- [Dominion High], 2008-06-06
- [Dominion High], 2008-06-06
- [Dominion High], 2008-06-06
- [Horizon Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Horizon Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [River Bend Middle], 2008-06-06
- [River Bend Middle], 2008-06-06
- [Ashburn Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Ashburn Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Ashburn Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Countryside Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Countryside Elementary], 2008-06-06
- [Countryside Elementary], 2008-06-06
- Emerick Elementary School, 2003
- Old Waterford School, 2003
- Waterford School, 2003
- Harper Park Middle School, 2003
- Ball's Bluff Elementary School, 2003
- Franzes Hazel Reid Elementary, 2003
- [Cool Springs Elementary School], 2008-08-22
- [Cool Springs Elementary School], 2008-08-22
- [Arcola Slave Quarters - Front], 2008-08-22
- [Arcola Slave Quarters - Front], 2008-08-22
- [Arcola Slave Quarters - Front/Side], 2008-08-22
- [Arcola Slave Quarters - Side], 2008-08-22
- [Arcola Slave Quarters - Back], 2008-08-22
- [Arcola Slave Quarters - Roof], 2008-08-22
- [Arcola Slave Quarters - Roof], 2008-08-22
- [Arcola Slave Quarters - Wall], 2008-08-22
- [Arcola Slave Quarters - Basement], 2008-08-22
- [Arcola Slave Quarters - Basement], 2008-08-22
- [Charles S Monroe Technology Center], 2009-04
- [Charles S Monroe Technology Center], 2009-04
- [Loudoun County High School], 2009-04
- [Stone Hill Middle School], 2009-04
- 2009-04[Leesburg Elementary School]
- [Rosa Lee Carter Elementary School], 2009-04
- [Steuart W Weller Elementary School], 2009-04
- Johnson's House of Beef 2009 [Johnson's Charcoal Beef House], 2009-04
- Johnson's House of Beef 2009 [Johnson's Charcoal Beef House], 2009-04
- [Blue Ridge Middle School], 2009-07-31
- [Blue Ridge Middle School], 2009-07-31
- [Blue Ridge Middle School], 2009-07-31
- [Emerick Elementary School], 2009-07-31
- [Emerick Elementary School], 2009-07-31
- [Hillsboro Elementary School], 2009-07-31
- [Hillsboro Elementary School], 2009-07-31
- [Hillsboro Elementary School], 2009-07-31
- [Hillsboro Elementary School], 2009-07-31
- [Lincoln Elementary School], 2009-07-31
- [Lincoln Elementary School], 2009-07-31
- [Lincoln Elementary School], 2009-07-31
- [Lovettsville Elementary], 2009-07-31
- [Lovettsville Elementary], 2009-07-31
- [Lovettsville Elementary], 2009-07-31
- [Lucketts Elementary], 2009-07-31
- [Lucketts Elementary], 2009-07-31
- [Lucketts Elementary], 2009-07-31
- [Round Hill Elementary], 2009-07-31
- [Round Hill Elementary], 2009-07-31
- [Round Hill Elementary], 2009-07-31
- [Round Hill Elementary water tower], 2009-07-31
- [Aldie Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Aldie Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Arcola Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Arcola Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Arcola Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Arcola Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Arcola Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Arcola Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Catoctin Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Catoctin Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Catoctin Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Creighton's Corner Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Creighton's Corner Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Creighton's Corner Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Creighton's Corner Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Kenneth Culbert Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Kenneth Culbert Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Kenneth Culbert Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Liberty Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Liberty Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Liberty Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Liberty Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Liberty Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Seneca Ridge Middle School], 2009-08
- [Seneca Ridge Middle School], 2009-08
- [Douglass School and Community Center], 2009-08
- [Douglass School and Community Center], 2009-08
- [Douglass School and Community Center], 2009-08
- [Douglass School and Community Center], 2009-08
- [Douglass School and Community Center], 2009-08
- [Douglass School and Community Center], 2009-08
- [Douglass School and Community Center], 2009-08
- [Evergreen Mill Elementary], 2009-08
- [Evergreen Mill Elementary], 2009-08
- [Evergreen Mill Elementary], 2009-08
- [J. Lupton Simpson Middle School], 2009-08
- [J. Lupton Simpson Middle School], 2009-08
- [Evergreen Mill Elementary School sign, Simpson Middle School across the street], 2009-08
- [Heritage High School], 2009-08
- [Heritage High School], 2009-08
- [Heritage High School], 2009-08
- [Potomac Falls High School], 2009-08
- [Potomac Falls High School], 2009-08
- [Guildford Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Guildford Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Creighton's Corner Elementary School], 2009-08
- [Creighton's Corner Elementary School], 2009-08
- [McDonalds, 335 E. Market St, prior to demolition], 2010-08
- [McDonalds, 335 E. Market St, prior to demolition], 2010-08
- [McDonalds, 335 E. Market St, prior to demolition], 2010-08
- [McDonalds, 335 E. Market St, prior to demolition], 2010-08
- [McDonalds, 335 E. Market St, prior to demolition], 2010-08
- [McDonalds, 335 E. Market St, prior to demolition], 2010-08
- [McDonalds, 335 E. Market St, prior to demolition], 2010-08
- [McDonalds, 335 E. Market St, prior to demolition], 2010-08